*dissonant violin chords
synced to a metronome*
Come closer,
elbows on the table.
Your colleagues at the front
think you're a malingerer.
You are a recipient
of the Iron Cross First Class.
A capable soldier.
A man like that wouldn't fake it.
Yet hypnosis works primarily
through the eyes.
In short, you cannot
hypnotize a blind man.
I cannot help you.
(Soldier) Staff Surgeon, sir.
Please.
I want to see again.
(whispering) Please.
*dramatic drumbeats*
Yes.
That would be a miracle.
You're hoping for a miracle?
Miracles don't happen anymore.
In our...
in our modern world.
Not for ordinary men,
but a man
of extraordinary willpower...
*Soldier breathes nervously.*
For him, there are no limits.
He throws off the shackles.
He tears down
the walls of the ordinary.
Examine yourself.
Do you believe you have that will?
*suspenseful music*
Then let us try.
*tones become brighter*
Open your eyes.
Try it.
*Doctor blows.*
Did you see the spark?
I don't know.
*music quickens*
Maybe a glimmer.
That's not enough.
That won't do.
In every man lies a god.
That is the will.
That is the energy.
Focus all that power inside you.
You feel this power.
You know this power
can accomplish superhuman feats.
Yes.
I know that.
The flame.
Do you see the flame?
I want to!
But...
*music intensifies dramatically*
*Soldier breathes heavily.*
You must see.
Anything is possible for you.
More.
*Soldier groans with effort.*
More!
*music stops abruptly*
*eerie music*
*rhythmic music*
*"Mir ist so nach dir"
by Mischa Spoliansky*
*lively music*
# I feel so much for you #
# I felt so much for you yesterday #
# And I always will #
# I'd love nothing more
than to be alone with you #
# And even if you laugh at it #
# And whatever you do against it #
# Today deep down inside me
I yearn for you #
# I don't know:
What's going on with you? #
# Going on with me?
Going on with me? #
# I don't know,
what's the matter with me? #
# And how about you,
me, me, me, me? #
When reporting the news, you have to
let the words float more freely.
Without bias, but with depth.
And with an awareness
of the drama of the moment.
That's your field.
I do the light entertainment.
Nonsense, you have the voice,
you're just holding back.
Besides, I have to prep the radio play
in Studio 2.
I can take care of that.
Gentlemen: our colleague Jacoby.
Morning...
- Morning.
The new voice of Germany.
Alright, focus, study the script.
Distance to the microphone.
Too far.
*music fades*
Attention, attention,
this is Funkstunde News.
It is Monday,
January 30th, 1933,
11:30 AM, dear listeners.
We turn our attention
to the events
unfolding at this hour
in the government quarter.
Will Reich President Hindenburg
appoint the leader
of the National Socialist
German Workers' Party,
Adolf Hitler,
as the new Reich Chancellor?
Excuse me, can I get through?
- Negotiations have been going on since morning.
Any news from the front?
Word on the street is
that Hitler is making
hard demands.
Such as?
- First and foremost, new elections.
And as soon as possible.
He won't be a chancellor
by Hindenburg's grace.
He wants the people to elect him.
- Yes.
*men whispering*
*door slams shut*
Dr. Forster?
Hello?
*suspenseful music*
Is someone there?
Hello?
*man breathes nervously*
*ominous tones*
*phone rings*
*she sighs*
Inspection A, Ritter speaking.
Who's there?
Hello.
What's going on?
(quietly) Dr. Forster wasn't there,
and the file wasn't either.
Police Precinct 5.
Yes, I...
I'd like to make
an anonymous report.
What exactly is this regarding?
A murder.
*suspenseful music*
*quiet murmuring*
What is he doing here?
Uh, the doctor, Forster...
- He wasn't there.
And the file?
We searched the whole clinic.
- We'll find him.
And the file.
The Führer is counting
on you personally, Blank.
*music fades out*
Take this down: Breaking news.
Berlin. The Reich President...
Field Marshal Hindenburg
has just appointed...
Adolf Hitler as Reich Chancellor
of Germany.
The new Reich Chancellor
has stipulated
that he will govern with
the majority support
of the German people.
Therefore, new elections have been
scheduled for March 5th.
He really won the old man over.
He didn't do it alone.
That was the work of many.
Back to work, Katelbach.
Yeah, already on it.
- See you at the Press Ball.
Not this time.
Personal obligations.
But I'll be there for the after-party
at Café Mutzbauer.
(scattered shouts) Heil!
*threatening music*
Here, 2:30, at Opernplatz.
*gloomy music*
Morning.
Morning, colleagues.
Which one of you took
the anonymous call?
I did, Mrs...
Detective.
Has anyone disturbed anything here?
No, we waited for you.
Good. Thank you.
What exactly
did the caller see?
That the doctor rushed away.
Down the stairs, that is.
I see.
Where's the body?
In the next room.
Let's get to work.
*she coughs*
*foreboding music*
*street noise*
*sinister sound*
Are you looking for me?
Then I bid you good day.
Officer!
I'm being followed.
- Is that so?
That SA man.
He's been following me.
Ever since I
got off the subway.
That guy? He's just looking.
I'm a lawyer.
You walk over to him
and take down his details.
Or I will take action against you!
*music turns restless*
(Woman) That would be the first proposal?
No, I want to know specifically
who I'm dealing with.
I don't need to know every detail.
We're not putting this man's first name
on page one, not a chance.
That's all we need.
(Woman) That's what I thought.
Alright, something like that.
Short and painful.
Excuse me, Mr. Editor-in-Chief.
- What is it?
The mugshot needs to go in.
The police insist on it.
Squeeze it onto the police page
and don't interrupt us
with such trifles, Potocznik.
Especially not on a day like this.
Otherwise, I also have
an advance review of
'The Testament of Dr. Mabuse'.
Masterpiece, Fritz Lang,
Rudolf Klein-Rogge,
front-page material, absolutely.
Tempo editorial desk?
Hello, please connect me
with the editor-in-chief, Mr. Heymann.
Our editor-in-chief
is very busy.
Would you please...
- It is of the utmost urgency.
Look,
I can't disturb him right now...
I have vital information
concerning the new government.
*he breathes shakily*
Excuse me,
Mr. Editor-in-Chief?
Potocznik!
I have someone on the line
who claims that...
I'll roast you on a spit
if you're pulling my leg.
We have mutual friends
from our university days.
The Dahlem circle.
- What was your name again?
Forster, Edmund.
Medicine. You were journalism.
New faculty.
And you were saying?
I possess information
of extraordinary gravity.
Sensitive regarding, against,
about, for what or whom?
The new Reich Chancellor.
Go on.
I must meet you
in a safe place.
Come here. To the newsroom.
Out of the question. Public.
Lots of people...
Anonymity, you understand?
Then come to the Press Ball.
You won't find a more anonymous place.
Understood.
Thank you.
*curious music*
*phone rings*
Institute for Suggestive Therapy.
Forster speaking.
Professor.
I need your help.
*door slams shut*
*ominous sounds*
*mysterious music*
Ah, Reinhold.
Well? How was the dentist?
No big deal.
A rotten molar.
With a sweet tooth like mine,
no surprise.
Did I miss anything today?
The change of government.
Hardly possible to miss
around town.
And a murder.
There's a prime suspect too.
I see.
Dr. Forster, Edmund.
An anonymous caller apparently saw
him leave the crime scene
in a hurry.
Is that so?
It's already gone out to the press.
Can you make copies of this
for tomorrow?
Yes, no problem.
*marching footsteps*
Institute for Suggestive Therapy?
It's me.
Strelow wasn't alone.
He was accompanied
by his SA squad.
You didn't hand over the package?
No.
It was impossible.
I understand.
I need to meet you.
Can you slip into the Press Ball
unnoticed?
I'll try.
Good.
Thank you, Gereon.
*sinister music*
Well...
*he starts up*
*indistinct voice on radio*
...from every walk of life,
marching past here,
workers of brain and brawn,
all class distinctions
have been erased.
It is a wind like there perhaps
once was in 1813.
When they said, the King called...
(Viennese accent)
This is unbearable.
New elections
in five weeks.
Which hardly makes it any better.
One more sip of lemon balm spirit
and by tomorrow morning
you'll be your old self again.
I mean your new self, uh...
good as new, I wanted to say.
Hold on, are you trying to kill me?
Soothingly caresses
the lining of your stomach.
Your hangover will be history faster
than this farce put on
by my unfortunate countryman.
I have to leave soon, unfortunately.
You just stay put
and let it work.
*soft piano music*
People heard
that Hitler had been appointed
Reich Chancellor,
that the Hitler-Hindenburg
agreement...
*keys rustling*
Finally.
I'm sorry.
If you only knew
what's going on out there.
Half the city is on the move.
Yes, I know.
But I'm here now.
How do I look?
*he huffs*
Dangerous.
And Jacoby still had tickets
for the Press Ball?
Apparently.
They're waiting for us.
We really have to hurry.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Then let's hurry up.
Come on, get dressed up.
*music fades*
*engine spluttering*
You have lipstick right there.
I hope it's mine.
Who knows where you've been
gadding about all day.
Did you hear?
Hitler is Chancellor.
Yes.
*suspenseful pulsing music*
*quiet chatter*
*voices grow louder*
Well?
Do you have the medical report?
It didn't work out.
What?
Why?
The doctor, Dr. Forster, has...
disappeared.
Quite a crowd here.
*opulent orchestral music*
Pretty close.
I've got this.
Pardon us, please.
It's my fault.
(Gräf) We're late too.
Together, please.
Let's mingle with the crowd.
*music becomes livelier*
*indistinct dialogue*
How's it going?
- Half of Tempo is here.
Where did you find her?
In the back of the clinic.
In bed,
wearing only a nightgown.
The doctor was seen
leaving the building in a rush.
Thank goodness, there you are.
That's him.
You won't believe this.
What?
That's him.
Who?
The doctor from the building today.
Are you sure?
His name is Dr. Forster.
Do you have your badge on you?
I always have it on me.
I don't.
You approach him, alright?
Alright.
You go up the left, I'll take the right.
Good.
I'll get Gräf.
Give me a head start.
Will do.
What?
- Take a look.
*murmuring*
I need your help.
Look up there.
(Gräf) Dr. Forster?
Come with me.
This gentleman's life is in danger.
You are being accused of a crime.
They want to silence me.
We have to leave right now.
You've got to be kidding.
He was right here a second ago.
I'll check over there.
Yeah.
*music turns more dynamic*
*music builds dramatically*
*music ends*
*she gasps*
*jazzy drum beats*
Gereon?
*music swells dramatically*
*music ends*
*dynamic lute music*
It's quarter past nine,
dinner was set for eight.
He's not here yet.
*he sneezes loudly*
*music fades, applause*
(Spectator) Bravo, Nyssen!
(Helga) Alfred.
Thank you from the bottom of our hearts.
I'm not playing another piece, though.
He said he'd come at eight.
Come now, take it easy,
my dear Nyssen.
New responsibilities,
new obligations.
You mean
one can just forget the old ones?
(Helga) He will come.
I have always found Mr. Hitler
to be very reliable.
As long as he
still needed our money, yes.
Let's just get started.
As we know, the Führer
doesn't care much for food.
Nor for this.
*subdued laughter*
My dear Göring,
this evening isn't about
stuffing our faces.
It is about
Mr. Hitler explaining to his backers,
or rather his benefactors,
how he will now,
since the hour has arrived,
lead Germany to where
we all envision it.
I personally handed him
a ten-point plan,
and now I'd like to know
in what stages
he will put it into effect.
Now that he is finally in the office
we put him in.
Excuse me for a moment.
- Of course.
Alfred, that wasn't very diplomatic
just now.
It's the only language
these parvenus understand.
Gentlemen,
you can call me
if the Herr Chancellor
decides to show up after all.
We should begin
before everything is overcooked
and loses all its flavor.
Please, we're serving.
If I may invite the guests to table,
dinner is served.
Thank you.
- Yes.
Rath was standing up on the gallery.
With Dr. Forster.
And someone else.
Then suddenly he vanished.
And?
Looked everywhere.
He must have arrested him.
The doctor?
Then he probably took him
to the Burg.
Safe to assume, yes.
No, he's not here.
Any notes?
Yes, let's take a look.
Hold on.
Nothing!
I'm sorry, Miss Ritter.
Yes, goodbye!
(Helga) Well then,
actually this evening we wanted
to hear from Mr. Hitler
how Germany's future
will become a new reality.
Now, of all people,
the key visionaries
are not present.
Perhaps you would like to speak,
honorable Reichstag President?
Dear Hermann Göring,
would you care to say a few words
befitting this momentous hour?
What is there to say?
Things will not remain
as they were.
*murmurs of agreement*
We must clean out the pigsty
bequeathed to us by the system,
and quickly.
We are not here
to administer justice.
Our only task is to destroy
and eradicate.
(Dr. Völcker)
I spent two years in Moscow.
For two years, I was prepared
for this exact day.
The line of General Secretary Stalin
and Chairman Thälmann
is unmistakable.
Escalation in this situation
would be entirely
the wrong approach.
(Man) Comrade Völcker!
The line from the leadership in Moscow
is not decisive here.
They're 2,000 kilometers
away from us.
The fight must be waged here and now
in the streets!
Exactly!
(Heymann)
Colleagues, friends, companions,
I fear this will all last
much longer
than most of us believe.
Yet we are not powerless.
Every one of us can make a choice
and never give an inch
to those who are now grasping
for power.
What we need is a powerful,
vehement sign
from many voices.
An appeal to reason
for the elections in five weeks.
*dark music*
We must mobilize
everyone we can.
In the coming days, we will replace
all police presidents
with men we can rely on.
Our esteemed retired Rear Admiral,
Herr von Levetzow,
will become Police President of Berlin.
(Göring) The political police will be
severed from standard administration
and replaced by
a Secret State Police Office.
Senior Government Councillor Wendt
will assume command.
SA units will be assigned
alongside police officers
to suppress the unrest
expected from the radical left
during the elections.
Police officers who use firearms
in the line of duty
will have my personal backing.
The election in five weeks
must be won.
That red scum cannot be allowed
to spoil our plans, can they?
(Man) Hear, hear!
*applause*
(Göring) Speaking of soup,
we shouldn't let it get cold.
Gereon?
*mournful piano music*
Can I get you anything else?
No, thank you.
*doorbell chimes*
*music fades out*
Excuse me,
I must have made a mistake.
Who are you looking for?
Gereon Rath. We had an appointment
and I'm late.
I need to pick something up.
What do you need to pick up?
Nothing. Excuse me.
*mournful piano music continues*
*